# ARAF AL-JAMI

arafaljami1331@gmail.com ♦ araf.aljami.me ♦ +8801755045141 ♦ Dhaka, Bangladesh

#### **SUMMARY**

Around 3 years of working experience as a software engineer, with a strong pursuit of problem-solving. Handson experience in building enterprise applications and maintaining best practices with OOD. Followed SOLID principles and design patterns to write clean, maintainable, and adaptive code.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: C#, Typescript, Javascript, Python, C/C++, Java

Specialties: .NET Core, IdentityServer4, Node js, Express, Flask, Git, Puppeteer, Angular, JMeter

Database and messaging: MongoDB, EF Core, MySQL, MassTransit, RabbitMQ, Mqtt, Azure Service

Bus.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Shohoj Limited, Dhaka

February 2020 - Present

Software Engineer, Backend

- · Developed **RESTful** and **gRPC APIs** in event-driven microservice architecture using ASP .NET Core.
- · Developed a service to provide **Identity Access Management** service for **millions of users**.
- · Developed tools to migrate millions of users from different user stores to 1 single consolidated user store.
- · Implemented a service to aggregate location history data in a friendly format for the data science team.
- · Wrote scripts/tools to load test services.
- · Used **Docker** to containerize services.
- · Used **TDD** to write robust, adaptable code.

## SELISE rockin' software, Dhaka

November 2018 - January 2020

Software Engineer

- · Used Angular, AngularJS to develop Single Page Applications
- · Used .NET Core technologies to develop REST API.
- · Worked on multiple projects and implemented business requirements for Selise Auditing and Certification Platform.

## **EDUCATION**

## Leading University, Sylhet

September 2014 - April 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

### AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

## **Onsite Competitive Programming Contests**

September 2014 - Present

- $\cdot$  10<sup>th</sup> place (4<sup>th</sup> place University wise) out of **150** teams at IUBAT ACM NCPC 2018. [link]
- $\cdot$  16<sup>th</sup> place (8<sup>th</sup> place University wise) out of **120** teams at MIST IUPC 2019

#### Online Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- · Active participant in online coding challenges on sites such as **TopCoder**, **Codeforces**.
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1982 (top 4%) in Codeforces. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1469 (Division 1) in TopCoder. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Solved around 2800 problems in various online judges. [link]